Guide to the William Martin Religious Right research collection, 1975-2000 MS 537
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series IV: Evangelists, 1975-1990 and undated (Boxes 99-121)
  - Subseries B: Subseries B: Other Evangelists (Boxes 110-121)
    - Rex Humbard, Sr. and Jr. (3 tapes). 5/22/75. Includes interviews with staff members, tour of facility in Akron suburb. (Box 120)
    - Falwell - tape 2 - interview 10/11/75 - Lynchburg, VA in airplane. (Box 120)
    - William Martin Religious Broadcasting Tapes (Box 120)
    - C.A. Roberts, 1975-08-04 (Box 120)
      Scope and Contents
      Expert in fundraising through direct mail and other methods. Houston-based. Was once elected head of Southern Baptist Pastors Conference, but did not serve after being accused of murdering his secretary, with whom he was having an affair, and her children. Evidence points to guilt. Had been chaplain of Bill Peterson's Florida football team (Florida, Florida State, Miami - not sure which). When Peterson came to Rice, Roberts came with him as a motivation coach, for one year. Died in auto accident, suspected suicide, drove under an 18 wheeler from parking spot under the overpass at 610 and 59, Houston. A fascinating man whom I got to know fairly well.
    - Ken Lybarger and Gerald Pope. 7/16/75. Direct mail (I think) (Box 120)
    - Notes from Tulsa newspapers on Oral Roberts, Billy James Hargis, and T.L. Osborne (Box 120)
    - More notes on Oral Roberts from newspapers. (Box 120)
    - Oral Roberts program after death of his daughter. Used the occasion to plead for money. (Box 120)
    - George Stovall. Executive in Roberts' ministry. 7/17/75 Tulsa. (Box 120)
    - Roberts Abstracts of notes. (Box 120)
    - Robert Liebert and Robert Schuller, presentation at 1980 National Council of Churches program on TV evangelism. (Box 120)
    - Paul Locke, "The Devil's Gospel" sermon (Box 120)
    - Russ Reid, expert on religious broadcasting. Cued me to small audiences, led to article in Atlantic, "Birth of a Media Myth." 1981 (Box 120)
    - National Religious Broadcasters (NRB) workshop on computers. Lester Sumrall inteview (Box 120)
    - NRB decency program. Cecil Todd. Notes on exhibits. (Box 120)
    - NRB. Gerald Ford Speech. Workshops. (Box 120)
    - Chris Panos, Houston evangelist (2) (Box 120)
    - Notes on T.L. Osborne Museum, Tula. Oral Roberts Chapel Speech, "The Roses will Bloom Again." (Box 120)
    - Richard Post, student at ORU. (Box 120)
    - Paul Schoch (?) interview 1975 (Box 120)
    - Robert Schuller interview 8/28/75 (Box 120)
    - James Robison Conference, Ft. Worth 1/30/81: Phyllis Schafley, Karen Davis (Wife of T. Cullen Davis, accused of multiple murders, gotten off with the aid of Richard "Racehorse" Haynes, despite eyewitness testimony.) Film: "The Family in Crisis." (Box 120)
    - William Martin Tapes on "Good News Texas" This was a Texas Baptist saturation evangelism campaign in 1976, involving billboards TV, print ads, etc. 6 tapes of interviews and notes. Resulted in cover story in Texas Monthly. Odd note: the PR man who served as my main contact with the ad company running the program was convicted of being the "Friendly Rapist" in Dallas and served a long sentence in the state penitentiary. I had not suspected him of such behavior. (Box 121)
    - PTL Scandal broke in 1987. 2 tapes of news, notes, and TV shows - Nightline and CNN. (Box 121)
    - National Conference (Box 121)
    - Garmer Ted (Box 121)
    - Stanley Rader - Lawyer, Business director (Box 121)
    - Al Carrozo - former minister (Box 121)
    - Conrad Comodu - HWA's pilot (Box 121)
    - Jas Robison (Box 121)
    - Cecil Todd (Box 121)
    - Jeremy Spencer (Box 121)
    - J. Harold Smith (Box 121)
    - CNN "Televangelism" 1981 (Box 122)
    - Robertson, Pat, on New Millennium (Box 122)
    - TV evangelist hearings, House Way and Means Committee, 10/6/87 (2) (Box 122)
    - 700 Club Telethon (Box 122)
    - Hunters service, with tongue-speaking (Box 122)
    - Larry Coyle, Consultant to religious broadcasters. 8/27/75 (2) (Box 122)
    - James Westmoreland. 9/17/98. Former associate of David Terrell. Disenchanted (3). (Box 122)
    - ABC "Pray TV" movie (Box 122)
    - "Healing" Channel 8 (Box 122)
    - Terrell, David. Prophecy. (Box 122)
    - Sutton, Hilton. Prophecy preacher, Houston (5). (Box 122)
    - Huckabee, Mike, while assistant to James Robison (Box 122)
- Series V: Fundamentalist Education, 1990-2000 (Boxes 122-124)
  - Mel and Norma Gabler 11/25/81. Interview at home in Longview (3). (Box 122)
  - Abstracted material from interviews and research (3) (Box 122)
  - Textbook hearings, Texas State Board of Education 8/9/82 (4) (Box 122)
  - Tapes from Home Schooling convention, Houston, 1998 (Box 122)
  - The McKims: Hope for the Family through Home Schooling (Box 122)
  - Mike Bolinsky: What Should Children Know about Science? (Box 122)
  - Tim Lambert: Home Schooling in Texas (Box 122)
  - Clay and Sally Clarkson: Home Alone: Biblical Foundations of Home Education (Box 122)
  - Summit Ministries: Relativism and the Loss of Truth (Box 122)
  - Schools, Schooling (Box 123)
  - Curriculum (Box 123)
  - Charter Schools (Box 123)
  - Colleges, Universities (Box 123)
  - Home Schooling (Box 123)
  - School Prayer (Box 123)
  - Public Education (Box 123)
  - Secular Humanism (Box 123)
  - Readings (Box 123)
  - School Boards (Box 123)
  - Sex Education (Box 123)
  - Vouchers (Box 123)
  - "The Family in America," 1991-92 (Box 124)
  - "Educational Pluralism in the South: Houston's Christian Schools," 1990 (Box 124)
  - "Freedom Writer," 1991-2000 (Box 124)
  - Summit Ministries Home Schooling Materials (2f) (Box 124)
  - Home School Catalogs (Box 124)
- Series VI: Publications (Boxes 125-127)
  - Chick Publications
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "Support Your Local Jew" (Box 125, Folder 1)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "Somebody Goofed" (Box 125, Folder 2)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "Soul Story" (Box 125, Folder 3)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "The Mad Machine" (Box 125, Folder 4)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "Bewitched?" (Box 125, Folder 5)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "Creator or Liar?" (Box 125, Folder 6)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "Escape!" (Box 125, Folder 7)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "The Beast" (Box 125, Folder 8)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "A Demon's Nightmare" (Box 125, Folder 9)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "Big Daddy?" (Box 125, Folder 10)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "The Thing" (Box 125, Folder 11)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "The Assignment" (Box 125, Folder 12)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "Are Roman Catholics Christians?" (Box 125, Folder 13)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "Hi There!" (Box 125, Folder 14)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "The Sissy?" (Box 125, Folder 15)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "One Way!" (Box 125, Folder 16)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "The Fool" (Box 125, Folder 17)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: Four Different Comics (Box 126, Folder 1)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "How to Get Rich (and keep it)" (Box 126, Folder 2)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "The Contract" (Box 126, Folder 3)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "Kings of the East" (Box 126, Folder 4)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "Happy Hour" (Box 126, Folder 5)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "Room 310" (Box 126, Folder 6)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "A Love Story" (Box 126, Folder 7)
    - J. T. C. Chick Comics: "This was your Life!" (Box 126, Folder 8)
    - Catholics and Chick Publications (Box 126, Folder 9)
  - Billy Graham Pamphlets
    - Billy Graham Pamphlets, 1951-1959 (Box 126, Folder 10)
    - Billy Graham Pamphlets, 1951-1959, 1962, 1971 (Box 126, Folder 11)
    - Billy Graham Pamphlets, 1960-1977 (Box 126, Folder 12)
  - Report of Kanawha County Board of Education (Box 126, Folder 13)
    Folder includes a report of a committee looking at English reading for the Kanawha County Board of Education and a number of complaints by conservative parents.
  - Focus on the Family publications
    - Focus on the Family Commentary (Box 127, Folder 1)
      Folder includes information Focus on the Family Commentary a more major part of more radio stations, including information about and by Dr. James Dobson.
    - Focus on the Family Report: Twice as Strong (Box 127, Folder 2)
      This research report is by Glenn Stanton from A Focus on the Family A Matter of Facts Report.
    - Focus on the Family Report: People make the World Better (Box 127, Folder 3)
    - Focus on the Family Report: News Media Miss the Mark on Partial-Birth Abortion Ban (Box 127, Folder 4)
    - Focus on the Family Report: "Only a Piece of Paper? The Unquestionable Benefits of Lifelong Marriage" (Box 127, Folder 5)
      Folder consists of a research report by Glenn Stanton from A Focus on the Family A Matter of Facts Report.
    - Focus on the Family Report: "Making the Grade: What Goals 2000 Means to Our Schools" (Box 127, Folder 6)
      Folder consists of a research report by Linda S. Page from A Focus on the Family A Matter of Facts Report.
    - Focus on the Family Report: "Condom Dangers: Debunking the 'Safe Sex' Myth" (Box 127, Folder 7)
      Folder includes a research report by Glenn Stanton from A Focus on the Family A Matter of Facts Report.
    - Focus on the Family Report: "You Bet Your Life: The Dangerous Repercussions of America's Gambling Addiction." (Box 127, Folder 8)
      This folder consists of a research report by Ronald A. Reno from A Focus on the Family A Matter of Facts Report.
    - Focus on the Family Report: "Before our Very Eyes: What TV Sex and Violence Are Doing to Us." (Box 127, Folder 9)
      Folder consists of a research report by Ronald A. Reno from A Focus on the Family A Matter of Facts Report.
    - Focus on the Family Report: "Setting the Record Straight: What Research Really Says About the Social Consequences of Homosexuality." (Box 127, Folder 10)
      Folder consists of a research report by Larry Burtoft, Ph.D, from A Focus on the Family A Matter of Facts Report.
    - Focus on the Family Report: "Bringing out the Worst in Us: The Frightening Truth About Violence, The Media and Our Youth." (Box 127, Folder 11)
      Folder consists of a research report by Bob Waliszewski and Jerry Melchisedeck from a Focus on the Family Culture Report.
    - Focus on the Family Research Briefs (Box 127, Folder 12)
    - Focus on the Family: Miscellaneous Publications (Box 127, Folder 13)
    - Focus on the Family: Magazines (Box 127, Folder 14)
    - Focus on the Family International (Box 127, Folder 15)
      This folder includes an international dispatch and other publications that try to sell Friends of the Ffamily style evangelical Christianity internationally.
  - Dobson Project: Brochures (Box 127, Folder 16)
  - Dobson General (Box 127, Folder 17)
    Folder includes booklets about Dobson, 8 publications from 1996 by Focus on the Family, and reports from Congress from A to Z.
- Series VII: Addendum (Boxes 128-130)
  - People for the American Way: Press Clips, 1988-10-1990-01 (Box 128, Folder 1)
  - People for the American Way Press Clips, 1985-07-1988-05 (Box 128, Folder 2)
  - Publications by Data Center, People for the American Way, and Social Issues Resources Series (Box 128, Folder 3)
  - Religion in America, The Princeton Religion Research Center, 1979-1980 (Box 128, Folder 4)
  - Religion in America, The Religion Research Center (Box 128, Folder 5)
  - Religion in America: The Gallup Report, 1984-03 (Box 128, Folder 6)
  - Religion in America: The Gallup Report, 1985-05 (Box 128, Folder 7)
  - Religion in America: The Gallup Report (Box 128, Folder 8)
  - Religion in America: The Princeton Religion Research Center, 1981 (Box 128, Folder 9)
  - Religion and Society Reports, 1989-12-1990-08 (Box 128, Folder 10)
  - Religion and Society Reports, 1986-02-1987-07 (Box 128, Folder 11)
  - Religion and Society Reports, 1986-12-1987-08 (Box 128, Folder 12)
  - (Failed) Undergraduate Curriculum Committee, 1995-1996 (Box 128, Folder 13)
  - Religious Right and Education (Box 128, Folder 14)
  - Right Wing Miscellaneous Booklets (Box 128, Folder 15)
  - School and Civic Prayer (Box 128, Folder 16)
  - Religious Right Miscellaneous Booklets, etc. (Box 128, Folder 17)
  - Rex Humbard (Box 128, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Figures (Box 128, Folder 19)
  - Kathry Kuhlman (Box 128, Folder 20)
  - Radio/TV Presenter Fundraising Techniques (1 of 2) (Box 128, Folder 21)
  - Radio/TV Present Fundraising Techniques (2 of 2) (Box 128, Folder 22)
  - Positive Thinking (Rough Manuscript) (Box 128, Folder 23)
  - Moral Majority Report (Falwell), 1980-07-1983-05 (Box 128, Folder 24)
  - "Things to Come: A Journal of Biblical Literature" - Microfiche (Box 128, Folder 25)
  - Receptivity to Religious Broadcasting - Microfilm (Box 128, Folder 26)
  - Swaggart VCR 1 (Box 129, Item 1)
  - Swaggart VCR 2 (Box 129, Item 2)
  - Swaggart VCR 3 (Box 129, Item 3)
  - VCR - Bill's Performance 60 Minutes, Frontline, Late Night (Box 129, Item 4)
  - VCR - Swaggart Documentaries (Box 129, Item 5)
  - VCR Swaggart, 1985-06 (Box 129, Item 6)
  - DVD - Assortment of Sermons, Jimmy Swaggart (Box 129, Item 7)
  - DVD - 60 Minutes Segment (Box 129, Item 8)
  - DVD - Jimmy Swaggart - "Big Time Religion" (Box 129, Item 9)
  - DVD - Give me that Big Time Religion, 1984-02-13 (Box 129, Item 10)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Joel Gregory, 1992-03-29 (Box 129, Item 11)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Gregory, 1991-11-13-1991-11-20 (Box 129, Item 12)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Joel Gregory, 1992-07-08-1992-07-15 (Box 129, Item 13)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Gregory, 1991-11-26-1991-12-01 (Box 129, Item 14)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Gregory, 1992-03-22 (Box 129, Item 15)
  - Cassette Tape (no case) - Dr. Joel C. Gregory, 1992-06-28 (Box 129, Item 16)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Joel C. Gregory, 1986-05-25 (Box 129, Item 17)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Joel C. Gregory, 1992-09-13 (Box 129, Item 18)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Gregory, 1991-11-24 (Box 129, Item 19)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Joel C. Gregory, 1992-08-23 (Box 129, Item 20)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Gregory, 1992-02-23 (Box 129, Item 21)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Joel Gregory, 1992-02-23 (Box 129, Item 22)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Gregory, 1992-02-16 (Box 129, Item 23)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Gregory, 1992-03-15 (Box 129, Item 24)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Joel C. Gregory, 1992-09-02-1992-09-27 (Box 129, Item 25)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Joel C. Gregory, 1992-03-08-1992-08-09 (Box 129, Item 26)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Gregory, 1991-12-08-1991-12-15 (Box 129, Item 27)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Joel Gregory, 1992-04-05 (Box 129, Item 28)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Gregory, 1992-03-08 (Box 129, Item 29)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Gregory, 1992-01-12 (Box 129, Item 30)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Gregory, 1992-07-19 (Box 129, Item 31)
  - Cassette Tape (no case) - Dr. Joel C. Gregory, 1992-07-12 (Box 129, Item 32)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Gregory, 1992-04-19-1992-04-22 (Box 129, Item 33)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Joel Gregory, 1992-05-06-1992-05-20 (Box 129, Item 34)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Gregory, 1992-02-09 (Box 129, Item 35)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Joel Gregory, 1992-08-12-1992-08-19 (Box 129, Item 36)
  - Cassette Tape - Dr. Gregory, 1992-05-10 (Box 129, Item 37)
  - Cassette Tape (Hal Lindsey Ministries) - Amageddon (Box 129, Item 38)
  - Cassette Tape (Times Square Pulpit) - The Vision David Wilkerson (Box 129, Item 39)
  - Cassette Tape - How to Profit from the Flight to Quality (Box 129, Item 40)
  - Cassette Tape - Osten Dallas (Box 129, Item 41)
  - Cassette Tape - Megan Day, Peg B (Box 129, Item 42)
  - Cassette Tape - Megan Day - Colorado Springs Citizens Group (Box 129, Item 43)
  - Cassette Tape - Megan Day (Box 129, Item 44)
  - Cassette Tape - David Epley - Healer (Box 129, Item 45)
  - Cassette Tape - Dodie Osteen, 2005-04-11 (Box 129, Item 46)
  - Cassette Tape - Paul, Lisa, Dodie Osteen, 2005-04-11 (Box 129, Item 47)
  - VHS tape - Franklin Graham, CNN People in the News, 2001-04-14 (Box 130)
  - Eikerenkoetter, Frederick (Rev. Ike)
    - Ike, Rev. (Box 130, Folder 1)
    - Eikerenkoetter, Fredrick (Rev. Ike) (Box 130, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Rev. Ike Documents (Box 130, Folder 3)
    - Field Notes (Box 130, Folder 4)
    - Science of Living (Box 130, Folder 5)
    - Press Clippings (Box 130, Folder 6)
    - Action Magazine (1 of 2) (Box 130, Folder 7)
    - Action Magazine (2 of 2) (Box 130, Folder 8)
    - Reverend Ike (Box 130, Folder 9)
    - Action Magazine, 1970-1975 (Box 130, Folder 10)
    - Reverend Ike Advertising Material (Box 130, Folder 11)
    - Action Magazine, 1972-1981 (Box 130, Folder 12)
    - Action Magazine, 1971-1977 (Box 130, Folder 13)
    - Rev. Ike's Success Number Booklets (Box 130, Folder 14)
    - Dr. Martin Article on Rev. Ike (Box 130, Folder 15)
    - Audio Rev. Ike Interview (1 of 3), 1969-11 (Box 130, Item 1)
    - Audio Rev. Ike Interview (2 of 3), 1969-11 (Box 130, Item 2)
    - Audio Rev. Ike Interview (3 of 3), 1969-11 (Box 130, Item 3)
    - Book - Health, Joy and Prosperity - For You! A Science of Living Study Guide by Rev. Ike (Box 130, Item 4)